## Hansdeep (Hans)

Phone: 0426676567, South East, Melbourne 3177

Email: hansdeep.singh@hotmail.com

Online portfolio-CV: <a href="https://www.hansdeep.pro">https://www.hansdeep.pro</a>

#### **ABOUT ME**

Over 5 years in Leadership and Over 17 Years of experience in Software Development including Web - Angular, MVC, ASP.net, .NET Framework, Cloud - AZURE Android, IOS development. Strong hold on current technologies, up for grabs into upcoming ones.

### Team management - Strategic planning - Decision making - Problem solving

#### **SKILLS**

- Building architecture around Microservices.
- Extensive experience in Azure DevOps and Azure Portal.
- Building own in-house .net Packages and Angular Libraries.
- Progressive-Web-Application which can be installed on Android and iOS devices, on all kinds of mobile phones, tablets and computers.
- Front-end responsive design based upon Google's Material design.
- C# clean code as programming language as back-end logic with Entity Framework. .net Factory pattern for dependency injection.
- Ability to be dependent upon by teammates and stake holders.
- Creation of Azure DevOps pipelines for CI/CD deployments.
- Extensive experience in Azure portal resources.
- Strong hold on .Net 6 + Web API applications.
- Strong hold on Angular 13 + /Typescript development.
- Token based and OpenID connect OAuth Authentications/Authorizations.
- Successful Integration with 3<sup>rd</sup> party applications example (Instructure, Microsoft 365 CRM, Qlik Sense server etc.)
- Strong hold on Back-end strategic design methodologies with MVC/MVVM Approach and Form based web applications (ASP.net).
- Strong hold on Front-end pixel perfect balanced interactive userinterface design, responsive on all screens and adapted for all devices e.g., Apple and Windows, with use of latest HTML5, CSS3, SASS
- JavaScript and Typescript (Angular)
- Strong hold on Relational Database management. Expert in running SQL queries.
- GitHub for repository update for version control.
- Quick learner I use latest web technologies and easily adapt to the new upcoming technologies.
- Excellent communication including the ability to distil technical details into easy human terms.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### LEAD, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

## Independent Schools Victoria

Oct 2022 – Current

- I am proud to have deployed our new isEducation platform (last year) for Independent Schools Victoria which is built on the latest technologies listed in my skill set. Taking lead on project development <a href="https://education.is.vic.edu.au">https://education.is.vic.edu.au</a>
- Development of in-house Angular TypeScript Libraries and .net NuGet packages.
- Managing team of developers and cloud engineers for building solutions for our schools/organisations.
- Interactions with Stakeholder and Non-Technical people on regular bases.
- Certificate in Agile Project Management.
- Taking lead on transitioning isEducation Suite from OLD MVC "Monolithic architecture" into NEW Angular PWA-Responsive (latest) front end and .net (latest) API. "Micro-services architecture"
- isEducation suite is built upon Azure B2C Tenant, OAuth2.0
   Authentication/Authorization. Where isEducation acts as an OAuth 2.0 server. Suite apps act as client applications.
- Taking lead on setting up Eco-System (Environments -Dev/UAT/Staging/Production) for isEducation suite applications.
- Setting up environment also includes creating Resources in Azure Portal and deploying website on relevant URLs.
- Building pipelines per isEducation Suite App per environment for CI/CD
- Collaborating with team of developers and cloud engineers for building solutions for our schools.
- Weekly scrum for monitoring on-going development and adhering to task deadlines.
- isEducation suite includes various products such as isLearn, isAnalyse, isConnect, isCommunicate, isRecruit, isPodcast, isArtwork
- API Integration with 3rd party tool (Qlik Sense Analytics)
- Maintenance of OLD isEducation suite built on Blazor Web Assembly from Microsoft and .net Framework.
- Development and version release of Xamarin Android Apps (isCommunicate) on Google Play

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### SENIOR DEVELOPER (Full Stack)

ComputerShare

- May 2020 -Sept 2022
- Working at ComputerShare's Utility department.
- Collaborating with a team of Senior developers and Solutions architect building solutions for our clients.
- Ongoing discussion with business analysts to keep with the scope of projects.
- Admin dashboards with charts and analytics data.
- Our systems provide billing services for Energy Industry (Gas, Electricity and Water) for clients such as SimplyEnergy, EnergyAustralia, UnityWater, HunterWater + (13 more)

- Ours is a Progressive Web App built on Angular 13, .net 6, C#
- We also built apps for Our Client's Field Sales which generally includes bill comparison.
- Ongoing support and monitoring of our systems.
- We use our own package libraries (Angular and .net)
- Continuous Integration and Deployment pipelines on Azure

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK .NET DEVELOPER**

**CPM Australia** 

Jan 2019 -April 2020

- Working alongside an established team of developers, interaction with marketing teams, graphic designers and business analytics team.
- Revamped Entire UI/UX Interface from scratch for all the applications currently being used at CPM which includes Mobile Apps.
- Developed CRM to manage in-bound calls for in-house **LOreal** CRM portal.
- Currently developing CRM for LOreal employees.
- Developed CRM features for Optus CRM, American Express, Subaru, AGL Gas, Saputo.
- Ongoing monitoring of servers, reporting and working along with Infrastructure team.
- Development of Mobile (iOS/Android) Apps with the use of Apache Cordova tools
- Expertise in web development using MVC and ASP.net, JavaScript/jQuery and other JavaScript libraries.
- Experience in .Net Core and Angular Apps.
- Working in an Agile Scrum based environment.
- Expert in SQL queries for update inserts and for a generation of reports.
- Providing ongoing support to the AMEX sales rep representatives.
- Angular Dashboards with .Net Core and live updates.
- Development of prototype UI / Projects to present to the stakeholders for future clients.
- Relational database designs, new and upgrading existing databases.

# FULL STACK .NET DEVELOPER/DIRECTOR (NZ)

**ExpertSystems Ltd** 

Sept 2013 -July 2018

- Development of various websites projects hosted on windows hosting servers.
- Responsible for client interactions, people management, including management of timelines for roll outs, and providing them with performance feedback.
- Implementing security role-based authorization and authentication.
- Developed an online roster system, with duty cards for NZ Bus. Reference Available.
- Web design from scratch. Use of Bootstrap and HTML5/CSS3 tools for fast-paced development.
- Graphic designing of Jerseys, Logos, Business cards, Posters, Wine bottle branding, Commercial advertisement designing for Magazine.

- 3-D Web-GL development to render Architecture Design with the use of Three.js, CSS3, HTML5
- Software development for outlined work, maintain and monitor software functionality, design and architecture.

## Website development/maintenance with logo/apparel design for the following: - (NZ)

**Team Sports Ltd** (Feb 2010 to Sept 2010)

 Team Sports is a Licensed distributor for Adidas gear and other sports goods.
 Designed posters, Caps and maintaining company website

Silver Fern Sports Ltd > Apparel design, website maintenance.

(Jan 2009 to April 2009)

My Biz Websites Ltd

(Feb 2008 to Jan 2009)

**BiscoPro Ltd** (July 2007 to Oct 2007)

My Biz Websites ➤ Sports club websites development, support and Logo design

During Study, developed a plugin for Google SketchUp software using Ruby on rails programming language and Google SketchUp API.

#### **EDUCATION**

A.I.S. St Helens Enterprise Award Graduate diploma in information technology (LEVEL 7), 10/2007 For all-round excellence, determination to succeed and general team spirit.

Punjab Technical University

**Technical** Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, 9/2006

-

**Cyber Security** 

Holmesglen institute Chadstone. Melbourne

Referees are available on request